Germain Vallverdu

Associate Professor -- PhD in Chemical Physics



10 août 1983, France Maried, 2 children

Contact

germain.vallverdu@univ-pau.fr (33) 5 59 40 78 51 (33) 6 88 59 08 87

> IPREM Technopôle Hélioparc 2 ave du Président P. Angot FR-64053 Pau cedex 9

Theoretical Chemistry

Computational strategy
Development
Surfaces, interfaces
VASP, CRYSTAL (solid)
Gaussian (molecule)
DL-POLY, AMBER (dynamic)

Programming

Fortran, C Python LATEX, HTML/CSS

Languages

French English (Professional)

On the web

orcid.org/0000-0003-1116-8776 •• gVallverdu •• gvallver.perso.univ-pau.fr

Abstract

Assistant professor at the Université de Pau et des Pays de l'Adour, I am a theoretical chemist at IPREM institute (Institute for Analytical sciences and chemical physics applied to environment and materials). My research activities concern the development of new methods and computational strategies at different time or space scales, applied to the investigations of complex systems. I teach mainly chemical-physics subjects and programming languages at the university of Pau.

Professional Experiences

since 2010 Université de Pau et des Pays de l'Adour

Pau, France

Associate professor

Theoretical chemistry and computational approaches. Surfaces, interfaces, reactivity and molecular interactions.

2009-2010 **CEA - DAM**

Bruyères le châtel, France

Postdoctoral position

Development and implementation of a mesoscopic model for reactive shock waves propagation in heterogeneous systems.

2006-2009 Université Paris-Sud 11

Orsay, France

PhD Student

Theoretical study of photophysical processes in fluorescent proteins.

Education

2006-2009	PhD in chemistry speciality theoretical chemi Mention très honorable	stry Université Paris-Sud 11
2004-2006	Master degree of chemistry speciality molecular chemical-physics Mention TB	Université Paris-Sud 11
2003-2004	Bachelor Degree of chemical-physics Mention TB	Université Paris-Sud 11
2003-2006	Magistère de Physico-Chimie Moléculaire	Université Paris-Sud 11 – ENS Cachan
2001-2003	Undergraduate physics and chemistry	Lycée François Arago, Perpignan

Main publications

Quesne-Turin, A. et al. Applied Materials & Interfaces 2018, Under Review.

Santos Silva, H. et al. Fuel 2017, 188, 374-381.

Vallverdu, G.; Minvielle, M.; Andreu, N.; Gonbeau, D.; Baraille, I. Surface Science 2016,

Guille, E.; Vallverdu, G.; Tison, Y.; Bégué, D.; Baraille, I. The Journal of Physical Chemistry C **2015**, 119, 23379–23387.

Martin, L.; Vallverdu, G.; Martinez, H.; Cras, F. L.; Baraille, I. Journal of Materials Chemistry **2012**, 22, 22063–22071.

Maillet, J. B.; Bourasseau, E.; Desbiens, N.; Vallverdu, G.; Stoltz, G. EPL (Europhysics Letters) **2011**, 96, 68007.

Vallverdu, G. et al. Proteins: Structure. Function, and Bioinformatics 2010, 78, 1040-1054.

Teaching

- Lectures in chemical-physics, theoretical chemistry, programming languages, in bachelor degrees, master degrees and doctoral school.
- Science popularization: Quantum mechanics, animations for secondary and primary school pupils